Fine Arts Federation of New York
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Fine Arts Federation of New York records
1895-2005
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Fine Arts Federation of New York
15.2 linear feet
The records of the Fine Arts Federation of New York, a consortium of New York City arts and architecture organizations, measure 15.2 linear feet and date from 1895-2005, bulk 1935-2002. The Federation's activities on behalf of the interests of the constituent organizations and the greater community are documented through officers' files, correspondence, administrative records, scattered printed materials, and scrapbooks.
Provenance
The Fine Arts Federation loaned materials for microfilming in 1968 and 1970; these same records were later donated, along with multiple accretions from 1978-2007 by former officers of the F.A.F., including Minor Bishop, Giorgio Cavaglieri, Margot Gayle, Lorrie Goulet, Katherine Thayer Hobson, Henriette Nathan, and Nanne Wollmann.
Separated Material
The Fine Arts Federation loaned materials to the Archives of American Art for microfilming in 1970 which are available on microfilm reel N70/16 and by interlibrary loan. These materials were not included in later donations and are not described in the container listing of this finding aid. They include correspondence with or related to the Municipal Art Society, mostly about the nomination of delegates to the F.A.F. and appointments to the New York City Art Commission and the mayor's Panel of Architects, 1961-1967; annual and semi-annual meeting reports for 1961-1965, and 1967; and an address by J. Roy Carroll, president of the American Institute of Architects, to the officers and board of the F.A.F., November 1963, concerning the artists-architect's role in society.
Related Material
Additional records related to the Fine Arts Federation of New York are found in the Architectural League of New York records, 1880s-1974.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings and electronic records with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Historical Note
The Fine Arts Federation of New York was established in 1895 "to ensure united action by the Art Societies of New York in all matters affecting their common interests; and to foster and protect the artistic interests of the community."
A consortium of New York City arts and architecture organizations, the F.A.F. has been responsible for saving historic buildings, promoting the arts, and providing a vision of the city's architectural future. The F.A.F. also provided delegate nominations to the New York City mayor for the Art Commission, a panel of architects and artists who reviewed proposed development to public property.
Presidents and other officers of the F.A.F. included Joseph H. Freedlander (1935-1937), A. F. Brinckerhoff (1937-1939), James C. Mackenzie (1940-1941), Wheeler William (1943, 1946-1948), Howard Greenley (Vice President, 1943-1944), Charles Downing Lay (Acting President, 1945), Richard Bach (1948-1950), Harvey Stevenson (1950-1951?), Giorgio Cavaglieri (1971-1974; 2001-2002), Margot Gayle (1974-1977), Nanne Wollmann (1992?-1994?), Roy Gussow (1996?-1997), and Lorrie Goulet (1997-2001), among others.
For many years in the mid-20th century, the Fine Arts Federation was located in the Architectural League of New York building on East 40th Street.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Fine Arts Federation of New York, a consortium of New York City arts and architecture organizations, measure 15.2 linear feet and date from 1895-2005, bulk 1935-2002. The Federation's activities on behalf of the interests of the constituent organizations and the greater community are documented through officers' files, correspondence, administrative records, scattered printed materials, and scrapbooks.
The records do not span the entire history of the F.A.F.; records prior to 1935 are few and scattered. Generally, the records document the activities of those officers' who served terms from the mid-20th century to the end of the century, and who maintained and donated their files to the Archives of American Art.
Presidents' Files contain scattered correspondence of F.A.F. presidents from 1935-early 1950s, and the files maintained or collated during presidental tenures from the 1970s and the 1990s-2000s. Secretaries' Files contain scattered records of various F.A.F. secretaries from the 1930s-early 1950s, and the files maintained or collated during particular secretaries' tenures from 1952-late 1970s and the early 2000s. Records in both series contain a variety of materials including administrative records, correspondence, meetings records, and subject files. Treasurers' Files include correspondence, two financial ledgers, lists of membership dues, and tax-related materials from 1915-1967.
The bulk of the Correspondence Series ranges from the 1930s-1960s and contains correspondence from constituent societies, special committees, and standing committees, as well as some miscellaneous chronological correspondence. Administrative Records include records related to the F.A.F. constitution and by-laws; meeting minutes and ancillary records; and project files from the late 1980s. Printed Materials include scattered announcements, catalogs, clippings, and pamphlets from the late 20th century to 2000s. Folders containing various types of records with little discernable order, a mélange of correspondence, drafts, meeting minutes, mimeographs, notes, reports, scattered clippings, transcriptions, and other documents, the bulk from the mid-1930s-1950s, comprise the Miscellaneous Series. There are also two photo scrapbooks documenting two separate events held in 1995.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 8 series:
Series 1: Presidents' Files, 1935-2002 (Boxes 1-3; 2.9 linear feet)
Series 2: Secretaries' Files, 1900-2002 (Boxes 3-9; 5.1 linear feet)
Series 3: Treasurers' Files, 1915-1967 (Box 9; 0.75 linear feet)
Series 4: Correspondence, circa 1914-2004, bulk 1930s-1967 (Boxes 9-12; 2.75 linear feet)
Series 5: Administrative Records, 1895, 1897, 1935-2005 (Boxes 12-14; 1.9 linear feet)
Series 6: Printed Materials, 1971-2005 (Box 14; 6 folders)
Series 7: Miscellaneous, 1914-1966, bulk mid-1930s-1950s (Boxes 14-15; 1.6 linear feet)
Series 8: Scrapbooks, 1995 (Box 16; 2 folders)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects-Topical:
Art, American; Art -- Societies, etc. -- New York (State) -- New York; Arts administrators
Types of Materials:
Photographs; Scrapbooks
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Presidents' Files, 1935-2002, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-3; 2.9 linear feet)
  Presidents' Files contain scattered correspondence of F.A.F. presidents from 1935-early 1950s, and the files maintained or collated during particular presidents' tenures from the 1970s and the 1990s-early 2000s.
  The series is arranged as 7 subseries chronologically by presidential term dates:
  1.1: Correspondence, 1935-1951
  1.2: Giorgio Cavaglieri (President, 1971-1974), 1971-1978
  1.3: Margot Gayle (President, 1974-1977), 1956-1979
  1.4: Nanne Wollmann (President, 1992?-1994?), 1979-1997
  1.5: Roy Gussow (President, 1996?-1997), 1996-1997
  1.6: Lorrie Goulet (President, 1997-2001), 1979-2001
  1.7: Giorgio Cavaglieri (President, 2001-2002?), 1964, 2001-2002
  - Correspondence, 1935-1951, 1.1:
    This subseries contains scattered correspondence of F.A.F. presidents from 1935 to the early 1950s. Folders are arranged chronologically by the presidential term.
    - Joseph H. Freedlander (1935-1937), 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - A.F. Brinckerhoff (1937-1939), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - James C. Mackenzie (1940-1941), 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wheeler Williams (1943, 1946-1948), 1943, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Howard Greenley (Vice President, 1943-1944), 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Charles Downing Lay (Acting President, 1945), 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Richard Bach (1948-1950), 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Harvey Stevenson (1950-1951?), 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Giorgio Cavaglieri (President, 1971-1974), 1971-1978, 1.2:
    The bulk of the materials found here are from Giorgio Cavaglieri's presidential tenure from 1971-1974, with scattered correspondence from his term as a board member from 1977-1978. Materials include correspondence, lists, meeting minutes, printed materials, and subject files. Records from Cavaglieri's 2001-2002 presidential term are found in subseries 1.7. Originally housed in three notebooks, the materials were disassembled and rearranged prior to processing. Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Board of Directors, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Committees, Lists of Members, Etc., circa 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1978, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
    - Family Court Building Sculpture Competition, 1971-1972, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
    - LaGuardia High School Art Competition, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Lists of Delegates, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Museum Symposium, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - New York Public Buildings, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Presidents of the 20 Constituent Societies, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Public Documents, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Speeches and Notes, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Margot Gayle (President, 1974-1977), 1956-1979, 1.3:
    This subseries contains materials from Margot Gayles' terms as secretary (1969-1973?) and president, including correspondence, lists, meeting minutes and ancillary materials, and subject files. Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - 1% for Beauty, 1965, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 2nd Sculpture Competition (1974), 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 80th Anniversary of the Fine Arts Federation, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - [Annual] Meeting (Apr. 24, 1969) [sound recording], 1969, (1 sound tape reel: 7-in. 1 1/2 mm) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Annual Meetings, 1969-1974, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 27-31)
    - Art Commission (1975), 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Art Commission, Names Proposed to Mayor, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Board Meetings, 1965, 1974, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
    - Chronological File: Meetings, Notices, Minutes, 1959-1974 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1979 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1979, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
    - Correspondence, President Giorgio Cavaglieri, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Legal Matters, 1964-1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Lists of Board Members and Delegates, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Lists of Delegates, 1960s-1975, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - Meeting, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Minutes, 1969-1977, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
    - "New Life for Plazas" Urban Design Unit, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Nominating Committee, 1970-1976, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 16-18)
    - Secretary Hobson's Records (1968-1969), 1956, 1963-1975 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Semi-Annual Meetings, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Villard Houses, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Nanne Wollmann (President, 1992?-1994?), 1979-1997, 1.4:
    Nanne Wollmann's subject files include meeting agendas, newspaper clippings, notes, and scattered correspondence. Folders are arranged according to their original order.
    - Subject Files, 1979-1997, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 22-26)
    - Subject Files, 1979-1997, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - Roy Gussow (President, 1996?-1997), 1996-1997, 1.5:
    Materials from Roy Gussow's log book include correspondence, meeting agendas and minutes, notes, and printed materials. The log book was disassembled during processing and the materials were kept in their original order.
    - Log Book, 1996-1997, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - Lorrie Goulet (President, 1997-2001), 1979-2001, 1.6:
    Lorrie Goulet's records consist of subject files and two folders of meeting minutes. The subject files, which were originally housed in binders, are comprised primarily of correspondence, as well as scattered printed materials, lists, and notes. The subject file binders were disassembled prior to processing. Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - #2 Columbus Circle, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - #10 Columbus Circle, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 14th Street Redevelopment, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 250 Water St., South Seaport Coalition, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 501 (c)(3), 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Art Commission, 1997-2001 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Art Commission, ALSA (Landscape Architect), 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Artists Equity Association (A.E.A.), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Artists Estate Tax, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Bank Account A.E.A. Matching Grant, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Brooklyn Bridge Park, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, Former Board Members and Guest Speakers, 1995-2001 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1998, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Directory Update (July 2, 1997), 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - F.A.F. and A.E.A. Centennial Dinner, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - F.A.F. Mailing List, Guest List, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Governors Island, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - History of F.A.F., 1996, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Hudson River Development, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Internet, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Letterhead Until June 2001, circa 1990s-2001 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Minutes, 1997-2001, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 29-30)
    - Miscellaneous, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - NYC Consolidated Centennial, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - NYU Law School, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Public Art Interest Network (P.A.I.N.)/Health and Hospitals Corporation (H.A.H.C.), Dr. Luis Marcos, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Queens' Queen, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Signage, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Train to Airport, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Wall Mural on S. Houston, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Giorgio Cavaglieri (President, 2001-2002?), 1964, 2001-2002, 1.7:
    These records were originally housed in three binders from which the materials were removed and the original order retained. Materials include correspondence, meeting minutes, and printed materials. Records from Giorgio Cavaglieri's presidential terms in the 1970s are found in subseries 1.2.
    - Binders #1-3, 1964, 2001-2002, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 39-41)
- Secretaries' Files, 1900-2002, Series 2:; (Boxes 3-9; 5.1 linear feet)
  Secretaries' Files contain records of various F.A.F. secretaries from the 1930s-early 1950s, and the files maintained or collated during particular secretaries' tenures from 1952-late 1970s, and the early 2000s.
  The series is arranged as 4 subseries chronologically by secretaries' term dates:
  2.1: General Secretaries' Files, 1900-1967
  2.2: Katherine Thayer Hobson (Secretary, 1952-1968), 1939-1972
  2.3: Minor Bishop (Secretary, 1974?-1978?), 1964, 1970-1978
  2.4: Henriette Nathan (Secretary, 2001?-2002?), 1980s-2002
  - General Secretaries' Files, 1900-1967, 2.1:
    The bulk of the material in this subseries is from the 1930s-1950s, with some scattered materials from 1963-1967. Found is correspondence, meeting minutes and ancillary materials, membership records, and printed materials. Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Agendas, 1932-1942, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Attendance, 1935-1950, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Circulars, 1935-1947 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1959, 1965-1967, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence re: Newsletter, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Form Letters, 1936-1940 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Members Deceased, 1935-1949, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Membership Lists, 1939-1943 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, Reports, Correspondence, 1928-1967, (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 8-12)
    - Notices of Meetings, 1927-1957, 1963-1967, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
    - Newspaper Clippings, circa 1913-1946, 1963-1967, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
    - Printers, 1935-1942 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Publications, 1916-1955 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Publications [Constitution and Rules of Procedure Booklets], 1900-1920, 1928-1949, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
    - Publicity, 1935-1940 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Katherine Thayer Hobson (Secretary, 1952-1968), 1939-1972, 2.2:
    Comprising the bulk of the series, Katherine Thayer Hobson's secretarial files range from the 1940s-1970s and contain correspondence, lists, meeting minutes and ancillary records, printed materials, and committee files. Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Action Opposing Destruction of Penn Railroad, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Amendments to the Constitution, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Amendments to the Constitution, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Annual and Semi-Annual Meetings (1961), 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting (1967), 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Application for Membership, 1939, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Art Commission, 1958-1959, 1965-1967, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - Art Commission, Architects, 1950s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Art Commission, Landscape Architects, 1950s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Art Commission, Laymen, 1950s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Art Commission, Lists of Candidates, circa 1958-1967 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Art Commission, Minutes, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Art Commission, Nominating Committee (1955-1960), 1953-1968 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Art Commission, Painters, 1950s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Art Commission, Sculptors, 1950s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Committee for Visual Arts, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Committees (1964-1966), 1957-1967 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Committees, Educational Council, 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1942-1968, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 18-20)
    - Correspondence [Disassembled Bound Materials], 1952-1956, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1968 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - E. James Gambaro Conference (1968), 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Financial Records, circa 1958-1969, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Forms and Notices [Includes correspondence and notes], 1940s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1942, 1961-1967, 1970, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 4-6)
    - Lists of Delegates, 1940-1966, (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 7-11)
    - Lists of Organizations, Officers, Delegates (1963-1964), 1962-1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Mayor's Panel of Architects, 1964-1967 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Meeting of Officers and Directors, 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Meetings, 1952-1972, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 15-18)
    - Minutes, 1942-1969, (10 folders) (Box 6, Folder 19-28)
    - Minutes, 1942-1969, (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1972, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
    - The Municipal Art Society, 1963-1968 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Nominating Committee for Officers and Directors, 1951-1969, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 11-13)
    - President, William F.R. Ballard, 1967-1969 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - President, Whitney North Seymour, 1959-1964 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Printed Materials, Booklets, 1963, 1966, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
    - Printed Materials, Bulletins, 1957-1967, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
    - Printed Materials, Newspaper Clippings, 1960s, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 20-21)
    - Reports, 1958-1962 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Reports for Constituent Societies, 1955, 1961-1964 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Responses to President Francis Keally's "A Recommendation", 1959, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Semi-Annual Meeting (1967, 1968); and Annual Meeting (1968), 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Semi-Annual Meeting (Nov. 21, 1968) [sound recording], 1968, (1 sound tape reel: 7-in. 1 1/2 mm) (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Tribute to Albert S. Bard, 1942-1963 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Minor Bishop (Secretary, 1974?-1978?), 1964, 1970-1978, 2.3:
    This subseries includes correspondence interspersed with scattered notices, lists, and printed materials; and meeting minutes of the Board of Directors. Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
    - Correspondence, 1964, 1970-1978, (8 folders) (Box 8, Folder 2-9)
    - Minutes, Board of Directors Meeting, 1972-1978, (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 10-15)
  - Henriette Nathan (Secretary, 2001?-2002?), 1980s-2002, 2.4:
    Materials from Henriette Nathan's terms as board member (1995?-1998?) and secretary are interfiled, and include correspondence, printed materials, some color photographs, scattered newspaper clippings, and biographical materials about board members. Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Board of Directors Archive, A-H, 1980s-2001, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 16-18)
    - Board of Directors Archive, I-P, 1995-2001 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Board of Directors Archive, Q-Z, 1991-2001 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Board of Directors Meetings, 2001-2002, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 21-24)
    - Correspondence, 1994-1999 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Events, 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - F.A.F. Miscellaneous, 1999-2002 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - F.A.F. Positions on Issues, 1994-2000 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - F.A.F. Presidents, 1994, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Printed Materials, A.E.A. "The Artists Proof", 2000 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Treasurers' Files, 1915-1967, Series 3:; (Box 9; 0.75 linear feet)
  Treasurers' Files include correspondence, two financial ledgers, lists of membership dues, and tax-related materials from the mid-1960s. Found is some correspondence of Treasurer E. James Gambaro, as well as some miscellaneous files of Gambaro's which were originally filed among the folders in Series 8.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Correspondence, 1926-1960, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 4-6)
  - Correspondence, E. James Gambaro, 1962-1967, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 7-9)
  - Financial Ledgers, 1915-1946, (2 folders; includes 2 ledgers) (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
  - Membership Dues, 1922-1960 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous [E. James Gambaro], 1919-1925, 1936-1967, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 13-15)
  - Tax File, 1963-1966 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, circa 1914-2004, bulk 1930s-1960s, Series 4:; (Boxes 9-12; 2.75 linear feet)
  Found is the correspondence of constituent societies, special committees, and standing committees, as well as some miscellaneous chronological correspondence. Interspersed among the correspondence are booklets, clippings, copies of draft and final legislation, lists, meeting minutes, notes, reports, and other printed materials.
  - Chronological, 1918-1967, (5 folders) (Box 9, Folder 17-21)
  - Chronological, 1936-1959, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
  - Chronological, 1995-2004 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Constituent Societies, Various, 1933-1967, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
  - Constituent Societies (Box 10)
    - American Fine Arts Society, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - American Institute of Decorators, 1942, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - American Society of Painters, Sculptors, and Gravers, 1936-1940 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - American Watercolor Society, 1936-1942 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Architectural League of New York, 1935-1951, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Beaux Arts Institute of Design, 1937-1942 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Brooklyn Chapter of the American Institute of Architects, 1936-1949, 1963-1967 (Box 10, Folder 14)